Guide to the Sarah Robinson Fay Swift Papers 1791-1804 MS 015 MS 015 MS 015
Cornwall Historical Society
Sarah Robinson Fay Swift Papers
1791-1804
Cornwall Historical Society
Fay Swift, Sarah Robinson (1751-1804)
MS 015
0.5 linear feet (1 box)
This collection contains items associated with Sarah Robinson Fay Swift (1751-1804).
Provenance
This collection came to the Cornwall Historical Society at an unknown date from the estate of Catherine Calhoun, who was the curator of the Torrington Historical Society. Ms. Calhoun passed away in 1986.
Access Restrictions
Open for research without restrictions.
Historical/Biographical Note
Sarah Robinson Fay Swift (1751-1804) was born on November 13, 1751 in Hardwick, Massachusetts to Samuel and Mercy Robinson, and removed with her family to Bennington, Vermont as a young woman. In Bennington, she married an attorney named Benjamin Fay, who passed away in 1786. Following his death, she married Heman Swift of Cornwall, and subsequently moved to his hometown. Sarah was Heman’s third wife, and was killed in a lightning strike at their home on April 17, 1804.
Scope and Content Note
The majority of items in this collection are letters sent to Sarah from her family in Vermont, including children from her first marriage, after she moved to Connecticut.
Arrangement
Folders are arranged chronologically by subject/author heading then chronologically within each subject/author heading.
The files are grouped into 4 series:
Fay Swift Correspondence with mother
Fay Swift Correspondence with siblings
Fay Swift Correspondence with children
Miscellaneous
Cornwall (Conn.)--history.; Correspondence; Fay Swift, Sarah Robinson (1751-1804); Fay Swift, Sarah Robinson (1751-1804)
- Correspondence between Sarah Swift and her mother
  - Letters sent to Sarah and Heman Swift from Mercy Robinson, 1791-1795; , undated (Box 1, Folder 1'-7)
- Correspondence between Sarah Swift and her siblings
  - Letters from brother J. Robinson, 1791-1795 (Box 1, Folder 8'-9)
  - Letter from S.R., 1792 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Letters from sister Anna Webster, 1795; , undated (Box 1, Folder 13-Nov)
  - Fragment of letter from unknown sibling, 1794 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Correspondence between Sarah Swift and her children
  - Letter from son Samuel, 1795 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Letter from M. Fay, undated (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Letters from unnamed children, 1793-1801 (Box 1, Folder 17-18)
- Miscellaneous Items
  - Letters sent to Sarah Swift from Mary Safford, undated (Box 1, Folder 19-20)
  - Note sent from Marcy Robinson to her granddaughter, undated (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Unsigned and letter, undated (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Memorial account detailing Sarah Swift’s fatal lightning strike, 1804 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Provenance of Sarah Robinson Fay Swift Papers, and background information on Swift, undated (Box 1, Folder 24)